UNDERGRADUATE CURRICULUM VITAE (CV) GUIDE ___

WHAT IS THE PURPOSE OF A CURRICULUM VITAE (CV)?

A CV is a standard document for presenting your qualifications for academic employment. It is a comprehensive overview of your academic and professional accomplishments, as opposed to a resume which is more of a qualification snapshot that is tailored to each position you apply to. Unless a CV is specifically requested, assume all academic positions at four year universities and some community colleges require CV's and all other positions require resumes.

WHEN TO USE A CV?

It is common to use when applying for:

- Academic and research positions
- Grants, fellowships, and awards
- Some graduate school programs
- Overseas employment and international organizations

FORMATTING A CV:

REQUIRED SECTIONS:

Name, Email, Phone number, Mailing address, Education, References, and Links to portfolio and/or LinkedIn

RECOMMENDED SECTIONS:

Publications, Dissertation/Thesis, Conferences, Presentations, Teaching Experience, Study Abroad, Lab or Specialized Skills, Academic Service,

Community Involvement, Certifications/Licenses/Credentials, Research Experience/Techniques/Interests, Membership or Professional Affiliations, Languages, Internships, Summary/Profile, Leadership, Volunteer Work, Fellowships or Grants, and Honors/Awards/Distinctions

CV VS. RESUME: WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE?

CV:

- Academic, Research, Scientific, and International Employment
- Detailed Summary: no page limit
- Goal is to construct scholarly identity
- Include References

Resume:

- Industry employment in the U.S.
- Brief synopsis: 1-2 pages maximum
- Goal is to construct a professional identity
- Do not include references



SAMMY SLUG

1156 High Street Santa Cruz, CA 95064 (831) 459-4420, sammyslug@ucsc.edu www.linkedin.com/sammyslug

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Environmental Science

June 2021

University of California, Santa Cruz

• Senior Thesis: Evaluating Energy Conservation for Electricity in the Santa Cruz County

AWARDS

• Dean's Honors

Fall 2019- Spring 2020

- Honors in the Major
- UC Santa Cruz College Scholars Program
- Golden Key International Honor Society

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant, UCSC Department of Environmental Studies Dec. 2018- Present Santa Cruz, CA

- Conduct weekly interviews with city residents to assess city residents' electricity usage
- Collaborate with research team to construct surveys on electricity usage for a sample of 100+ households monthly
- Analyze and compile data in organized reports to inform policy recommendations

Fieldwork Assistant, UCSC Department of Environmental Studies Sept. -Dec 2018 Santa Cruz, CA

- Evaluated and revised UCSC campus Environmental Impact Report
- Collected surface groundwater samples from the American River and analyzed for pesticide contamination

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Conservation Outreach Intern, Center for Biodiversity & Conservation March 2018-Present Santa Cruz, CA

- Create and implement program of applying remote sensing GIS applications to biodiversity conservation
- Develop targeted strategies incorporating city and county advice aimed at reaching out to government officials, citizens, and community educators

Waste Consultant, Ecology Now

Jan. 2016-March 2018

Santa Cruz, CA

- Recruited businesses and non-profits to participate in free water waste audit and performed waste audits
- Educated local citizens of environmental issues in person and via telephone

- Wrote weekly press releases and sponsored educational events to promote environmental stewardship
- Updated and maintained Santa Cruz client contact database with 500+ clients

POSTER PRESENTATIONS

"Legal, Technical, and Economic Challenges in Integrating Renewable Power Generation into the Electricity Grid," 4 San Diego Journal of Climate & Energy Law 1-68, Spring 2013 (with Tim Duane).

PROFESSIONAL AFFILATIONS

Member, National Association of Environmental Professionals (NAEP) Member, Association of Environmental Studies & Sciences (AESS)

SKILLS

Computer: Proficient in Microsoft, SPSS, JAVA, and GIS Language: Fluent in French and Conversational in Spanish

REFERENCES

John Smith
Assistant Professor, Department of Environmental Studies
Relationship: Faculty Advisor
1156 High St.
Santa Cruz, 95064
831.459.4420
jsmith@ucsc.edu

Tim Duane
Professor, Environmental Studies Department
Relationship: Professor
1156 High St.
Santa Cruz, 95064
831.459.4420
tduane@ucsc.edu

Madeleine Fairbairn
Assistant Professor, Environmental Studies Department
Relationship: Faculty Mentor
1156 High St.
Santa Cruz, 95064
831.459.4420
mfairbairn@ucsc.edu

